Finding Aid for Robert H. Brucker papers, 1914-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert H. Brucker papers 1914-1967
Brucker, Robert Hawn, 1888-1967.
4 linear feet
85897 Aa 2
Saginaw, Michigan, attorney, aide and political advisor to his brother, Governor Wilber M. Brucker. Diaries, notebooks, correspondence and photograph albums concerning in part the political career of his brother.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came to the library from Mrs. Clara Brucker (donor no. 3767 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert H. Brucker was a Saginaw, Michigan, attorney, aide and political advisor to his brother, Governor Wilber M. Brucker.
The collection includes the following series: Diaries; Notebooks containing letters exchanged between Robert and Wilber Brucker; Photograph albums; and Miscellaneous notebooks and other volumes.
Subjects:
Brucker, Robert Hawn, 1888-1967.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Elections--Michigan--1930.; Lawyers--Michigan--Saginaw.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Republican Party (Mich.); Saginaw (Mich.); World War, 1914-1918.; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects: Visual Materials
Brucker, Ferdinand, 1858-1904.; Brucker, Robert Hawn, 1888-1967.; Brucker, Wallace H.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Brucker family.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; Military officers.; Law offices--Michigan--Saginaw.; Saginaw (Mich.)--Law offices.; Saginaw (Mich.)--Tombs and sepulchral monuments.; Tombs and sepulchral monuments--Michigan--Saginaw.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Diaries, 1930-1959
  - 1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956 (Box 1)
  - 1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
- Notebooks containing letters exchanged between Robert and Wilber Brucker, 1914-1959
  - 1914-1919 (Box 2)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 2)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 2)
  - 1936 (Box 2)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - 1939 (Box 2)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  - 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 2)
  - 1953-1955 (Box 2)
  - 1956 (Box 2)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 2)
- Photograph albums
  - 1957 and undated; include pictures and autographs of prominent personalities (Box 3)
  - Undated; include family pictures (Box 3)
  - Undated; include pictures and autographs of family and prominent personalities (Box 3)
  - Undated; include pictures and autographs of family and prominent personalities (Box 3)
  - 1930s include pictures of the Brucker family (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous notebooks and other volumes, 1906-1966
  - Undated; include correspondence, photographs and assorted miscellanea (Box 3)
  - 1927-1965 include correspondence and photographs (Box 4)
  - 1957-1960 include miscellaneous correspondence (Box 4)
  - 1965-1966 include miscellaneous correspondence (Box 4)
  - 1932-1962 include miscellaneous correspondence, photographs and clippings (Box 4)
  - Notebook, 1960s concerning the Michigan National Bank (Box 4)
  - Saginaw High School Yearbooks, 1906 (Box 4)
  - Address book, undated (Box 4)